压制：GREENOTEA　特效字幕：GREENOTEA
欢迎访问x265编码影视交流论坛：www.greenotea.com
怪兽电力公司
- 晚安 宝贝儿  - 晚安 妈妈
- Good night, sweetheart.  - 'Night, Mom.
好梦 孩子
Sleep tight, kiddo.
演习结束
Simulation terminated.
演习结束 演习结束
Simulation terminated. Simulation terminated.
演习结束
Simulation terminated.
好了 贝尔先生 是吗?
All right. Mr. Bile, is it?
我朋友都叫我"软软"
My friends call me Phlegm.
贝尔先生 你能告诉我你哪里做错了吗?
Mr. Bile, can you tell me what you did wrong?
- 我摔倒了?  - 不 不 在那个之前
- I fell down?  - No, no, before that.
谁能告诉我贝尔先生错在哪?
Can anyone tell me Mr. Bile's big mistake?
有人吗?
Anyone?
我们再看一遍录像带吧 开始了
Let's take a look at the tape. Here we go.
就是这儿
Right there.
看到了吗? 那扇门 你没关门
See? The door. You left it wide open.
而员工不关门
And leaving the door open is the worst mistake
是最严重的错误 因为...
any employee can make because...
呃 风会钻进来?
Eh. It could let in a draft?
因为小孩会跑出来
It could let in a child.
沃特努斯先生
Oh. Mr. Waternoose.
人类小孩是最有害 最致命的
There's nothing more toxic or deadly than a human child.
一触即死
A single touch could kill you.
不关门的话 小孩子就会走进这家工厂
Leave a door open and a child could walk right into this factory,
走进怪兽世界
right into the monster world.
我不要去小孩的房间 你不能强迫我
I won't go in a kid's room. You can't make me.
你必须去 因为我们需要这个
You're going in there because we need this.
我们的城市要靠你们去收集孩子的尖叫
Our city is counting on you to collect those children's screams.
没有尖叫 就没有能源
Without scream we have no power.
是的 这是项危险的工作
Yes, it's dangerous work.
因此 我需要你们竭尽全力
And that's why I need you to be at your best.
我需要自信的 执着的 凶猛的...
I need scarers who are confident, tenacious, tough...
还要吓人的怪兽
and intimidating.
我需要像... 詹姆斯·P·苏利文那样的怪兽
I need scarers like... like James P. Sullivan.
嘿 早安怪兽都市 现在是怪兽市
Hey, good morning, Monstropolis. It's five after the hour of 6:00 a.m.
早晨6:05
in the big Monster City.
温度适宜 华氏65度 适合你们爬行动物
The temperature's a balmy 65 degrees which is good news for you reptiles.
看起来今天很适合躺在床上睡个懒觉
And it looks like it's gonna be a perfect day to maybe, hey, lie in bed, sleep in,
或者解决那一坨赖在床上的肥肉!
or simply work out that flab that's hanging over the bed!
起床了 小苏!
Get up, Sulley!
我确定我没预约叫醒服务 小迈
I don't believe I ordered a wake-up call, Mikey.
少说话 多运动 棉花糖小子!
Less talk, more pain, marshmallow boy!
感受脂肪的燃烧 就这表现还敢自称怪兽?
Feel the burn. You call yourself a monster?
轻手轻脚 轻手轻脚 轻手轻脚 孩子醒了!
Scary feet, scary feet, scary feet. The kid's awake!
轻手轻脚 轻手轻脚 轻手轻脚 孩子睡着了!
Scary feet, scary feet, scary feet. Kid's asleep!
双胞胎! 在双层床上!
Twins! In a bunk bed!
我以为你会中计 忘记吓唬其中一个
I thought I had you there.
好了 小苏 开始了 准备好了吧? 跟着它 在这里
OK, Sulley, here we go. You ready? Follow it. It's over here.
在那里 别让小孩子碰你 别让他碰到你!
Over there. Don't let the kid touch you. Don't let him touch you!
不知道为什么大家都这么说 我喜欢吓唬睡梦中的小孩
I don't know but it's been said I love scarin' kids in bed.
加油 打败牙菌斑 打败牙菌斑
Come on. Fight that plaque, fight that plaque.
吓人的怪兽没有牙菌斑
Scary monsters don't have plaque.
118下 你能做到119下吗?
One-eighteen. Do you have 119?
第120下在哪里?
Do I see 120?
- 哦 真难以置信  - 我还没流汗呢
- Oh. I don't believe it.  - I'm not breaking a sweat.
没说你 快看! 新的广告开播了
Not you. Look! The new commercial's on.
怪兽公司前途一片光明
The future is bright at Monsters, Incorporated.
- 我坐这 我坐这  - 我们是您生活的一部分
- I'm in this one, I'm in this one.  - We're part of your life.
我们为您的汽车加油 为您的家庭供暖
We power your car. We warm your home.
为您的城市供电
We light your city.
- 我是怪兽公司的一员  - 嘿 看! 是贝蒂!
- I'm Monsters, Incorporated.  - Hey, look! Betty!
精心为每个孩子挑选与之搭配的理想怪兽
Carefully matching every child to their ideal monster,
从而获得高质量的尖叫
to produce superior scream.
进而提炼为清洁可靠的能源
Refined into clean, dependable energy.
每当您打开任何东西 您都能看到怪兽公司的影子
Every time you turn something on, Monsters, Incorporated is there.
- 我是怪兽公司的一员  - 我们了解我们面临的挑战
- I'm Monsters, Incorporated.  - We know the challenge.
纯真之窗正在逐渐紧闭
The window of innocence is shrinking.
人类儿童越来越难以吓到
Human kids are harder to scare.
当然 怪兽公司已准备好应对未来
Of course, MI is prepared for the future.
我们拥有着最顶尖的怪兽
With the top scarers,
最好的提炼厂
the best refineries,
我们还研究全新能源技术
and research into new energy techniques.
好了 我要出现了
OK, here I come.
今天 我们为了更好的明天而努力
We're working for a better tomorrow, today.
我们来自怪兽公司
We're Monsters, Incorporated.
我们是MI 怪兽公司
We're MI, Monsters, Incorporated.
我们吓人 因为我们关注
We scare because we care.
- 我简直无法相信  - 迈克
- I can't believe it.  - Oh Mike.
我刚才出现在电视上了!
I was on TV!
你看到我了吗? 我是个天才
Did you see me? I'm a natural.
喂? 我知道! 我是不是很帅?
Hello? I know! Wasn't I great?
你们全家都看了吗? 是你妈妈
Did the whole family see it? It's your mom.
哈哈... 我还能说什么? 摄像机就是喜欢我
Haha... what can I say? The camera loves me.
我告诉你 大个子
I'm telling you, Big Daddy,
你以后会在电视上经常看到我这张脸的
you're gonna be seeing this face on TV more often.
是吗? 在怪兽都市的通缉令上?
Yeah? On the Monstropolis' Most Wanted?
你自从四年级开始就嫉妒我帅气的容貌了
You've been jealous of my good looks since the fourth grade.
- 祝你一天愉快 亲爱的  - 你也是 亲爱的
- Have a good day, sweetie.  - You too, hon.
- 好了 小苏 上车吧  - 不要
- OK, Sulley, hop on in.  - Nope.
嘿 嘿 嘿 你去哪 你要去哪?
Hey, hey, hey, where you going, where you going?
小迈 有条超级近路
Mikey, there's a scream shortage.
- 我们走路过去  - 走路?
- We're walking.  - Walking?
- 是的  - 不 不要  - 来吧
- Yep  - No, no.  - Come on.
我的宝贝儿 你看 他需要人去驾驶他
My baby, look, he needs to be driven.
我的宝贝儿 再联系
My baby. I'll call you.
- 嘿 你想知道我为什么买车吗?  - 不想
- Hey, you wanna know why I bought the car?  - Not really.
就是为了开它啊
To drive it.
在街上 你可以按喇叭 滴滴 哔哔
You know, like on the street with the honk-honk and the vroom-vroom
- 不用走路  - 让它休息会吧 好吗 小胖子?
- no walking involved.  - Give it a rest, will ya, butterball?
你可以顺便运动
Come on. You could use the exercise.
我可以顺便运动? 看看你
I could use the exercise? Look at you.
你 你情况特殊
You, you have your own climate.
有多少只触角跳过了绳子?
How many tentacles jump the rope?
早上好 迈克 早上好 小苏
Morning, Mike. Morning, Sulley.
早上好 孩子们 过得好吗?
Morning, kids. How you doing?
- 再见 迈克 再见 小苏  - 嘿!
- Bye, Mike. Bye, Sulley.  - Hey!
混蛋
Nuts.
- 嘿 嘿 嘿 伙计们  - 嘿 托尼
- Hey, hey, hey. Fellas.  - Hey, Tony.
嘿 托尼 托尼
Hey. Tony, Tony.
我听说有人快要打破尖叫纪录了哦
I hear somebody's close to breaking the all-time scare record.
我只是想确保我们有足够的尖叫
Just trying to make sure there's enough scream to go around.
- 嘿 免费的  - 嘿 谢了
- Hey, on the house.  - Hey, thanks.
小菜一碟
Bada-bing.
尼玛
Oh, great.
嘿 泰德 早上好
Hey, Ted, good morning.
看到了吗 小迈? 泰德也走路去上班
See that, Mikey? Ted's walking to work.
那不算什么 这家伙走五步就到公司了
No big deal. This guy takes five steps and he's there.
怪兽电力公司
怪兽公司 请稍等
Monsters, Inc. Please hold.
怪兽公司 请稍等 怪兽公司 请稍等
Monsters, Inc. Please hold. Monsters, Inc. Please hold.
- 早上好 小苏  - 早上好 瑞奇
- Mornin', Sulley.  - Mornin', Ricky.
- 这不是苏利文嘛  - 吓人车间见 伙计
- It's the Sullster.  - See you on the scare floor. Buddy.
- 嘿 玛吉 陪审团的工作怎么样?  - 早上好 小苏
- Hey Marge. How was jury duty?  - Morning, Sulley.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 它还是在向左歪
Hey. It's still leaning to the left.
- 才没有  - 嗨 伙计们 嗨 杰瑞
- It is not.  - Hey, fellas. Hey, Jerry.
早上好
Morning.
- 嘿 苏利文先生  - 伙计们 我都说了 叫我小苏就好
- Hey, Mr. Sullivan.  - Guys, I told you, call me Sulley.
- 那多不好  - 我们就是想祝您今天好运
- I don't think so.  - We just want to wish you good luck today.
嘿 嘿 你俩别说了 你们会让他无法专心工作的
Hey, hey, come on, get lost, you two. You're making him lose his focus.
- 真抱歉  - 回见 伙计们
- Sorry.  - See you later, fellas.
加油 苏利文先生
Go get 'em, Mr. Sullivan.
安静 你会让他无法专心工作的
Quiet. You're making him lose his focus.
- 哦 不 对不起!  - 闭嘴!
- Oh, no. Sorry!  - Shut up!
怪兽公司 请稍等 怪兽公司 我会联系您
Monsters, Inc. Please hold. Monsters, Inc. I'll connect you.
费尔蒙戈小姐正在度假 您需要给她留言吗?
Miss Fearmonger is on vacation. Would you like her voicemail?
- 小甜甜  - 大眼儿熊
- Schmoopsie-pooh.  - Googly bear.
- 生日快乐  - 大眼小亲亲 你居然记得
- Happy birthday.  - Googly-woogly, you remembered.
- 嘿 苏苏小亲亲  - 嘿 希莉娅小亲亲
- Hey, Sulley-wulley.  - Hey, Celia-wheelia.
- 生日快乐  - 谢谢
- Happy birthday.  - Thanks.
那么 我们今晚有哪些特殊庆祝活动呢?
So are we going anywhere special tonight?
我就打算我们在一个小地方庆祝 叫哈利豪森之家
I just got us into a little place called Harryhausen's.
哈利豪森之家? 没人能预定到那里的
Harryhausen's? But it's impossible to get a reservation there.
对大眼儿熊来说可不是难事 下班我来接你
Not for googly bear. I will see you at quittin' time.
- 绝对准时  - 好的 宝贝儿
- Not a minute later.  - OK, sweetheart.
想想浪漫的事
Think romantical thoughts.
# 你和我 我和你 #
# You and me. Me and you #
# 两人在一起 #
# Both of us together #
你知道吗 伙计 她就是我命中注定的爱人
You know, pal, she's the one.
- 就是这样的 她就是那个人  - 我真为你感到高兴
- That's it. She is the one.  - I'm happy for you.
谢谢你帮我预定到座位
Thanks for hooking me up with those reservations.
不用谢 预订人的名字是"大眼儿熊"
No problem. They're under the name "googly bear."
好想... 那一点都不好玩
Good ide... You know, that wasn't very funny.
- 什么...  - 华斯基
- What the...  - Wazowski.
你知道吗?
What do you know?
我不仅吓小孩子 也吓小怪兽哦
It scares little kids and little monsters.
我才没被吓到 我就是有点过敏
I wasn't scared. I have allergies.
- 那是当然  - 嘿 兰德尔 留着在吓人车间表演吧 好吗?
- Sure.  - Hey, Randall, save it for the scare floor, will ya?
我今天可是在巅峰状态 苏利文 得做几个极其惊悚的吓人动作
I'm in the zone today, Sullivan. Gonna do serious scaring.
- 得几个高分  - 哇 兰德尔 那真不错
- Putting up some big numbers.  - Wow, Randall, that's great.
等我们破了纪录就能让你更丢脸了 哈哈
That should make it more humiliating when we break the record first. Ha ha.
听到了吗? 风向变了
Do you hear that? It's the winds of change.
"听到了吗? 风向变了..."
"You hear that? It's the winds of..."
真是个讨厌鬼 以后我一定会
What a creep. One of these days I am really
让你给他点教训
gonna let you teach that guy a lesson.
亲爱哒 宝贝儿
Chalooby. Baby.
早上好 萝丝 我亲爱的花园肉肉小蜗牛
Good morning, Roz, my succulent little garden snail.
- 今天我们要吓谁?  - 华斯基
- Who would we be scaring today?  - Wazowski.
你昨天晚上没有上交你的报告
You didn't file your paperwork last night.
哦 那个该死的报告
Oh, that darn paperwork.
让它随风吹走不更好吗?
Wouldn't it be easier if it all just blew away?
不准再犯
Don't let it happen again.
不会了 嗯 我下次会注意的
Yes. Well, I'll try to be less careless.
我盯着你呢 华斯基
I'm watching you, Wazowski.
一直都在盯着你
Always watching.
- 她是个疯子  - 一直
- She's nuts.  - Always.
所有吓人车间都已启动
All scare floors are now active.
助理人员 请汇报工作站情况
Assistants, please report to your stations.
好了 同志们 即将连线东海岸
OK, people, Eastern Seaboard coming online.
怪兽准备出场
We got scarers coming out.
唔 他们真是太帅了
Oooh. They are so awesome.
嘿 祝最厉害的怪兽能够获胜
Hey, may the best monster win.
正有此意
I plan to.
倒计时开始 七 六 五
We are on in seven, six, five,
四 三 二...
four, three, two...
你最棒 你最棒 你毛茸茸的最棒了
You're the boss, you're the boss. You're the big hairy boss.
我今天感觉一级棒 小迈
I'm feeling good today, Mikey.
太好了 下扇门马上来了
Attaboy, attaboy. Another door coming right up.
你还是差一点 兰德尔
You're still behind, Randall.
- 或许我该重新排列尖叫...  - 别废话 再给我放一扇门下来
- Maybe I should realign the scream...  - Just get me another door.
门 好的 门
The door, yes, door.
杰瑞 目前进度如何?
Well, Jerry, what's the damage so far?
我们马上就要完成今天的计划了 先生
We may actually make our quota today, sir.
本月首次
First time in a month.
- 怎么了?  - 那个小孩差点就碰到我了
- What happened?  - The kid almost touched me.
- 就差那么一点  - 她都不怕你?
- She got this close to me.  - She wasn't scared of you?
- 她才6岁  - 我差点就死了
- She was only six.  - I could have been dead.
- 我差点就死了  - 冷静点 老兄
- I could have died.  - Keep it together, man.
嘿 这扇门失败了
Hey, we got a dead door over here.
- 我来了  - 小心
- I'm coming.  - Look out.
借过
Excuse us.
本周我们有58扇门失败 先生
We've lost 58 doors this week, sir.
现在的小孩啊
Kids these days.
不像以前那么容易受惊吓了
They just don't get scared like they used to.
粉碎她
Let her rip.
- 先生?  - 什么?
- Sir?  - What?
看
Look.
注意 新任怪兽领袖诞生了
Attention. We have a new scare leader.
是兰德尔·鲍格斯
Randall Boggs.
看看那些数字
Look at those numbers.
睡衣派对
Slumber party.
当我没说
Never mind.
嘿 注意点
Hey, watch it.
詹姆斯 那真是令人印象深刻的表现
Well, James, that was an impressive display.
不 我只是在做我的本职工作 沃特努斯先生
No. Just doing my job, Mr. Waternoose.
都是您栽培得好
'Course I did learn from the best.
如果我不能在5秒内看到一扇新的门出现在我的工作站
If I don't see a new door in my station in five seconds,
我会亲自把你丢进粉碎机里
I will personally put you through the shredder.
嘿 华斯基 干得不错 那些数字真漂亮
Hey, Wazowski, nice job. Those numbers are pretty sweet.
是吗? 我都没怎么注意
Are they? You know, I hadn't even noticed.
- 那乔治怎么样?  - 他干得很棒
- And how's Georgie doing?  - He's doing great.
我喜欢和这个大家伙合作
I love working with that big guy.
要保持门源源不断 查理 我今天运气超好
Keep the doors coming, Charlie. I'm on a roll today.
乔治和我就像兄弟 2319号警报!
George and I are like brothers. 2319!
2319号警报!
We have a 2319!
红色警报
Red alert.
红色警报 红色警报
Red alert, red alert.
- 红色警报  - 乔治·桑德森
- Red alert.  - George Sanderson.
请保持原地不动 准备清除污垢
Please remain motionless. Prepare for decontamination.
保护自己 同志们!
Duck and cover, people!
竟然惊动了儿童检测署
Oh. Not the CDA.
儿童检测署
- 快 快 快  - 行进中 靠边站
- Go, go, go.  - Coming through. Stand aside.
- 撤离污染区域的人员  - 不
- Clear the contaminated area.  - No.
- 确认2319号警报  - 人员已撤离 行进中 小心
- A 2319 in progress.  - Area Clear. Coming through. Watch yourself.
退后 小心
Stand back. Careful.
清理完毕 状态为990 除污就绪
All clear. Situation is niner-niner-zero. Ready for decon.
- 多谢了 伙计们 刚才真是危险  - 好了
- Thanks, guys, that was a close one.  - OK.
好了大家 休息一会
Ok, people. Take a break.
车间关闭半小时 重启系统
We gotta shut down for half hour and reset the system.
整个吓人车间暂停任务
An entire scare floor out of commission.
还能更糟吗?
What else can go wrong?
- 今天糟透了  - 困难只是暂时的 先生
- What a day.  - We're just going through a rough time, sir.
大家都知道您会领导我们渡过难关的
Everyone knows you'll get us through it.
去向董事会说吧
Tell that to the board of directors.
詹姆斯 我的家族掌控这家公司有三代了
James, this company's been in my family for three generations.
我会不惜一切保全这个公司
I would do anything to keep it from going under.
我也会的 先生
So would I, sir.
- 你可以帮我做些事  - 愿意效劳 先生
- I could use your help with something.  - Anything, sir.
你看 我们招了些新怪兽员工
You see, we've hired some new scare recruits,
坦白说 他们... 呃... 他们
and frankly, they're... eh... they're
- 经验不足?  - 不 他们水平太臭了
- Inexperienced?  - No, they stink.
我想 你可以明天过来坐坐
I thought maybe you might come by tomorrow
向他们展示展示
and give them a demonstration.
告诉他们如何才能成为我们最厉害的怪兽
Show them what it takes to be our top scarer.
我会用传统的沃特努斯式的跳跃和咆哮开场
I'll start out with the old Waternoose jump and growl.
好孩子
Now that's my boy.
结束了 同志们 所有的门都必须回到原处
Let's go, everybody. All doors must be returned.
所有的门
No exceptions.
我还没见过你像今天这么厉害呢 你刚才运气真不错 老兄
I've never seen anything like you today. You were on a roll, my man.
再来一天像这样的状态 尖叫最高纪录就能收入囊中了
Another day like this and that scare record's in the bag.
没错 宝贝儿
That's right, baby.
这么说吧 我觉得光吃完饭还不够
Lets's get this. As if dinner wasn't enough,
吃完我要带她去怪兽拉力赛看看
I'm taking her to a monster truck rally afterwards.
- 不错  - 你打算做什么?
- Nice.  - What's on your agenda?
- 我会回家 再做些运动  - 还做运动?
- I'm going home. Work out some more.  - Again?
你懂吗 生活不仅仅只有吓人
You know, there's more to life than scaring.
能借下你的香水吗?
Can I borrow your odorant?
好啊 我有臭垃圾味的 还有陈年垃圾桶味的
Yeah, I got smelly garbage or old dumpster.
你有低潮味吗? 不然湿狗味的?
You got low tide? How about wet dog?
好 熏起来
Yep. Stink it up.
我说 我有时太浪漫了 我觉得我真应该和自己结婚
You know, I am so romantic sometimes I think I should just marry myself.
- 消停一会  - 一个多么浪漫的夜晚在等着我
- Give me a break.  - What a night of romance got ahead of me.
今晚是我和希莉娅的夜晚
Tonight is about me and Celia.
爱情的小船已经准备起航了
The love boat is about to set sail.
我要告诉你 兄弟 她那美丽的面容
'Cause I gotta tell you, buddy, that face of hers,
让我的心...
it just makes my heart go...
你好 华斯基 今晚计划了很多娱乐活动?
Hello, Wazowski. Fun-filled evening planned for tonight?
嗯 事实上...
Well, as a matter of fact...
我相信你一定已经准确无误地提交了你的报告
And I'm sure you filed your paperwork correctly,
难得一回
for once.
你的沉默已经肯定了这一点
Your stunned silence is very reassuring.
完了 我的吓人报告 我把它们忘在桌上了
Oh, no. My scare reports. I left them on my desk.
如果我不能在五分钟内赶到的话 他们就要取消我的预约了 我该怎么办?
If I'm not at the restaurant in five minutes they'll give our table away. What am I gonna do?
- 小甜甜  - 嘿 大眼儿熊
- Schmoopsie-pooh.  - Hey, googly bear.
- 要走了吗?  - 我曾经... 就是有一点...
- Want to get going?  - Do I ever... It's just...
- 什么?  - 好吧 就是...
- What?  - OK, it's...
- 就是一点小...  - 我不明白
- It's just a small...  - I don't understand.
就是我忘了交一些报告
It's just I forgot about some paperwork I was supposed to file.
迈克提醒了我
Mike was reminding me.
- 谢了 伙计  - 是吗?
- Thanks, buddy.  - I was?
我是说 是的 没错 是的
I mean, I was. Yeah. I was.
- 好 我们走吧  - 马上
- OK. Let's go.  - We're going.
在我桌上 小苏 粉色的给财务部
On my desk, Sulley. The pink copies to accounting.
紫红色的给采购部 深黄色的给萝丝
The fuchsia ones go to purchasing and the goldenrod ones go to Roz
留下深褐色的
Leave the puce.
粉色的给财务部 紫红色的给萝丝
Pink copies to accounting, fuchsia ones to Roz.
不 紫红色的给采购部
No. The fuchsia ones go to purchasing.
深黄色的给萝丝
The goldenrod ones go to Roz.
老兄 我不知道深褐色是什么颜色
Man, I have no idea what puce is.
哦 那就是深褐色
Oh, that's puce.
喂?
Hello?
有人吗? 这有一扇门
Anyone? There's a door here.
嗨? 嘿
Hello? Hey.
有怪兽在这吓人吗?
Anybody scaring in here?
嗨
Hello. Yo.
猫咪
Kitty.
不要 不 别过来
No, no, stay back.
等等 等等
Hold it, hold it.
哦 迈克 我过过很多生日... 好吧 也没那么多生日
Oh, Michael, I've had a lot of birthdays... Well, not a lot of birthdays.
但这是有史以来最好的一次生日
But this is the best birthday ever.
你在看什么?
What are you looking at?
我刚想到我第一次见到你的时候
I was just thinking about the first time I laid eye on you,
- 你多美啊  - 得了吧
- how pretty you looked.  - Stop it.
- 那时你的头发更短  - 我正想剪
- Your hair was shorter.  - I'm thinking about getting it cut.
不 不用 我喜欢这个长度
No, no, I like it this length.
我喜欢你的一切
I like everything about you.
前几天有人问我怪兽都市里最美丽的是谁
Just the other day someone asked me who I thought the most beautiful monster was in Monstroplis.
- 你知道我说了什么?  - 你说了什么?
- You know what I said?  - What did you say?
我说...
I said...
- 小苏?  - 小苏?
- Sulley?  - Sulley?
不 不是 我想说的不是这个
No, no, that's not what I was gonna say.
你莫名奇妙
You're not making sense.
- 他很帅 他很壮  - 好巧啊 遇到你了
- He's handsome. He's rugged.  - What a coincidence, running into you.
- 我正要打包点吃的带走  - 迈克
- I'm just gonna order something to go.  - Michael.
- 这有什么好吃的?  - 离开这 你把一切都毁了
- What's good here?  - Get out of here. You're ruining everything.
我回去找你的书面报告时 那儿有一扇门
I went to get your paperwork and there was a door.
什么?
What?
- 一扇门?  - 兰德尔在里面
- A door?  - Randall was in it.
等等 兰德尔? 他作弊 他想提高他的分数
Wait a minute. Randall? That cheater. He's trying to boost his numbers.
- 还有点事  - 什么?
- There's something else.  - What?
看俺滴包里
Ooklay in the agbay.
- 什么?  - 看袋子里
- What?  - Look in the bag.
什么袋子?
What bag?
这儿没有我喜欢吃的 但是保重 希莉娅
They don't have anything I like here. But take care, Celia.
- 发生了什么?  - 希莉娅 请你理解下
- What's going on?  - Celia, please try to understand.
- 我有些事需要处理!  - 迈克?
- I have to do something!  - Michael?
数到三 一 二...
On three. One, two...
- 小孩!  - 嘣!
- A kid!  - Boo!
有小孩!
A kid!
这有小孩 一个人类小孩!
There's a kid here. A human kid!
大眼儿熊!
Googly bear!
跟我来
Come on.
哈利豪森之家
赶紧离开这
Let's get out of here.
请保持冷静 这不是演习
Please remain calm. This is not a drill.
7835号警报 请指示
7835 in progress, please advise.
- 迈克? 迈克!  - 希莉娅!
- Michael? Michael!  - Celia!
- 请跟我来  - 别推我
- Please come with me.  - Stop pushing.
嘿 别碰我的小甜甜
Hey. Get your hands off my schmoopsie-pooh.
清场完毕 准备清除污垢
Area clear. Ready for decontamination.
我觉得这约会再糟糕不过了
I don't think that date could have gone any worse.
如果目击证人可信的话 现在有一个漏网的小孩
If witnesses are to be believed, there has been a child security breach
这在怪物史上前所未有
for the first time in monster history.
我们既无法证实也无法否认今晚这儿有小孩
We can neither confirm nor deny the presence of a human child here tonight.
好吧 一个小孩从我上方飞过 用激光眼引爆了一辆汽车
Well, a kid flew right over me and blasted a car with its laser vision.
我想跑开 但是它用意念把我拎起来
I tried to run from it, but it picked me up with its mind powers
像玩偶一样摇晃
and shook me like a doll.
这是真的 我都看到了
It's true. I saw the whole thing.
我的专业观点是现在是恐慌的时候了
It is my professional opinion that now is the time to panic.
它来了 它来了!
It's coming. It's coming!
嘣!
Boo!
不要啊 不要!
No, no, no, no!
孩子 过来
Come here, kid.
不许碰 你这个小...
Don't touch those, you little...
那些已经按字母顺序整理过了 没关系 没关系
Those were alphabetized. It's OK. It's all right
只要它不靠近我们 我们就没事
As long as it doesn't come near us we're gonna be OK.
你喜欢这个? 去捡吧
You like this? Fetch.
嘿 嘿 够了 没人可以碰小小迈
Hey, hey. That's it. No one touches Little Mikey.
迈克 把熊给她
Mike, give her the bear.
哦 不要!
Oh, no!
让它停下来 小苏 让它停下来!
Make it stop, Sulley. Make it stop!
嘿 看 看到熊吗? 乖乖熊
Here, look. See bear? Nice bear.
小苏!
Sulley!
熊熊 他是一只快乐熊
Bear, he's a happy bear.
他没哭 你也不能哭 否则我们就有麻烦了
He's not crying, neither should you.Or we'll be in trouble
因为他们会发现我们 所以拜托你现在别哭了 拜托
'cause they're gonna find us, so please stop crying now. Right now
很好 很好 小苏 继续 你做得很好
Good. Good, Sulley. Keep it up. You're doing great.
他是一只快乐熊 他没有...
He's a happy bear. He has no...
- 它碰到我了  - 小苏 熊!
- It touched me.  - Sulley, the bear!
熊 给她那个...
The bear. Give her the...
那是什么?
What was that?
我不知道 但是如果它不再这么做那就太好了
I have no idea, but it would be really great if it didn't do it again.
我怎么会干这事? 我怎么会这么傻?
How could I do this? How could I be so stupid?
这会毁了公司的
This could destroy the company.
公司? 谁还管公司啊?
The company? Who cares about the company?
我们怎么办? 那可是杀怪兽机器
What about us? That thing is a killing machine.
我打赌它只是在等着我们睡着 然后砰!
I bet it's just waiting for us to fall asleep and then wham!
我们是唾手可得的猎物 我的朋友 唾手可得的猎物 活靶子
We're easy prey, my friend. Easy prey. We're sitting targets.
好 看看 我想我有计划了
OK, look, I think I have a plan here.
我们用汤匙 在城市下方挖一个地道
Using mainly spoons, we dig a tunnel under the city
把它放回野外
and release it into the wild.
汤匙
Spoons.
就这样了 我已经绞尽脑汁了 就差那么一点 气球太贵
That's it. I'm out of ideas. we are closed. Air balloon, too expensive.
巨型弹弓又太明显 特洛伊木马又太希腊化了
Giant slingshot, too conspicuous. Enormous wooden horse, too Greek.
不行 想不出 想不出了
No. Can't think. Can't think.
- 快死了 要死了  - 迈克?
- Flatliner. Flatlining.  - Mike?
我想她累了
I think she's getting tired.
那你为什么不找个地方给它睡
Well, then why don't you find someplace for it to sleep
让我安心想办法!
while I think of a plan!
你困了吗? 想睡觉了?
Are you sleepy? Wanna sleep?
你是想睡了吗?
Is that what you want?
好 我来为你准备一个舒服的地儿...
OK. I'll make a nice little area for you to...
不行 嘿 那是我的床 你会弄得整床都是细菌的
No. Hey, that's my bed. You're gonna get your germs all over it.
好吧 反正我的椅子更舒服
Fine. My chair's more comfortable anyway.
什么?
What?
那只是一个衣柜 你能睡觉了吗?
It's just a closet. Will you go to sleep?
嘿 那像是兰德尔
Hey, that looks like Randall.
兰德尔是你害怕的怪兽
Randall's your monster.
你认为他会从衣柜进来吓唬你
You think he's gonna come through the closet and scare you.
哦 天哪 我要怎么解释呢?
Oh, boy, how do I explain this?
它是空的
It's empty.
看到没?
See?
这儿没有怪兽
No monster in here.
好吧 现在有了
Well, now there is.
但我不会吓唬你
But I'm not gonna scare you.
我下班了
I'm off duty.
好吧
OK.
要不我坐在这等你睡着?
How about I sit here until you fall asleep?
睡吧 睡觉去
Go ahead. Go to sleep.
现在 睡吧
Now. Now go.
你去睡觉
You go to sleep.
迈克 也许这听起来很疯狂 但是我觉得那个小孩并不危险
Mike, this might sound crazy, but I don't think that kid's dangerous.
真的吗? 好吧 那样的话 我们让它留下
Really? Well, in that case, let's keep it.
我一直都想要一只会杀了我的宠物!
I always wanted a pet that could kill me!
这样 不如我们把她送回门里?
Now, look, what if we just put her back in her door?
- 什么?  - 迈克 想想吧
- What?  - Mike, think about it.
我们把她送回去后 就像没发生一样 一切都恢复正常了
We send her back just like it never happened,everything goes back to normal.
是开玩笑吗? 告诉我你在开玩笑
Is that a joke? Tell me you're joking.
小苏 我觉得鉴于现在这情况
Sulley, I think that given the circumstances
到目前为止我已经算是非常宽容了
I've been extremely forgiving up to now.
但那是一个很可怕的主意
But that is a horrible idea.
我们怎么做? 带着它大摇大摆地走?
What are we gonna do? March in public with that thing?
估计那样我们就轻轻松松地进工厂 是吗?
Then I guess we just waltz right up to the factory, right?
我没法相信我们就要这样进工厂
I can't believe we are waltzing right up to the factory.
小苏 一个拖把 两灯泡和沙发皮
Sulley, a mop, a couple of lights and some chair fabric
可骗不了人 想想一些人
are not gonna fool anyone. Just think about a few names.
尼斯湖水怪 大脚 可怕的雪怪
Loch Ness. Bigfoot. The Abominable Snowman.
他们都有一个共同点 伙计 都被驱逐出境了!
They all got one thing in common, pal. Banishment!
- 接下来可能就是我们  - 别恐慌 我们能做到
- We could be next.  - Don't panic. We can do this.
- 嘿 过得怎样 弗兰克?  - 嘿 伙计
- Hey, how you doing, Frank?  - Hey, guys.
肯定没事的
Everything's going to be OK.
一号要在这里取指纹
Number one wants this place dusted for prints.
- 小心  - 我看得很清楚
- Careful with that.  - I got a good view from here.
再低一点
A little lower.
这个是在现场找到的
This was recovered at the scene.
- 别慌 别慌  - 别和我说
- Don't panic. Don't panic.  - Don't tell me not to panic.
- 保持理智  - 理智个屁
- Just keep it together.  - It's not OK.
- 嘣  - 可能已被污染
- Boo.  - Could be contaminated.
先生们 安全是我们第一要务
Gentlemen, safety is our number-one concern.
如果有任何... 现在没空 我...
If there's anything that... Not now. I'm...
哦 你好 小可爱
Oh, hello, little one.
- 你从哪里来啊?  - 沃特努斯先生!
- Where did you come from?  - Mr. Waternoose!
啊哈 詹姆斯 这是你的?
Aha, James, is this one yours?
事实上 这是我堂姐的
Actually, that's my cousin's sister's
- 女儿 先生  - 嗯 今天是...
- daughter, sir.  - Yeah, it's...
带远亲来厂参观的日子
Bring an Obscure Relative to Work Day.
我肯定忘写备忘了 好吧 听着 詹姆斯
Must have missed the memo. Well, listen, James,
不如午饭后过来演习车间
why don't you stop by the simulator after lunch today
给我们演示下怎么吓唬人? 之前我和你说过了
and give us that scare demonstration we talked about?
是 是的 先生...
Yeah. Oh, sir...
- 沃特努斯先生?  - 好吧 好吧 我来了
- Mr. Waternoose?  - Yes, yes. I'm coming.
我们下午见 詹姆斯
I'll see you this afternoon, James.
前提是这些人没关闭我们的工厂
That is, if these gentlemen haven't shut us down.
- 天哪  - 吓人演示
- Oh, boy.  - A scare demo.
很好 为什么我是最后一个知道的?
That is great. Why am I the last to know?
我们可以带你堂妹的女儿一起去 她会是一大亮点
We could bring your cousin's sister's daughter along. She'll be a big hit.
站住
Halt.
抓住他
Hold him down.
来吧 没危险
Come on. The coast is clear.
好 现在我们要做的就是摆脱它
OK. All we have to do is get rid of that thing.
在这等着 我去拿门卡
So wait here while I get its card key.
她不能待在这 这是男更衣室
She can't stay here. This is the men's room.
这是你说过的最奇怪的话
That is the weirdest thing you've ever said.
没事 没关系的 看 它多喜欢这儿 它高兴得跳舞呢
It's fine. It's OK. Look. It loves it here. It's dancing with joy.
拿到门卡我就回来
I'll be right back with its door key.
这个舞蹈好可爱 看上去就像你要...
That's a cute little dance. It almost looks like you've got to...
你好了没?
Are you done in there?
对不起 对不起
Sorry, sorry.
好 你现在好了 是吧?
OK. You're finished now, right?
嗨?
Hello?
嘣
Boo.
她去哪了?
Where did she go?
她消失了吗?
Did she disappear?
还是隐身了?
Did she turn invisible?
我真想不出啊
I just have no idea.
抓到你了
Gotcha.
嘣
Boo.
嘿 你真厉害
Hey, you're good.
放松 放松 放松
Be relaxed. Be relaxed. Be relaxed.
萝丝 我那温柔的花朵 你今天看起来太美了
Roz, my tender oozing blossom. You're looking fabulous today.
这是新发型吗? 说吧 告诉我 这是新发型 对吧?
Is that a new haircut? Come on, tell me, it's a new haircut, isn't it?
肯定是新的化妆品 你拉皮了 整形了 你肯定做了什么
It's got to be new makeup. You had a lift. You had a tuck. You had something.
你打了什么让你看起来像...
Something has been inserted in your skin that makes you look like...
听着 我需要你帮助 兰德尔昨晚在吓人车间工作
Listen, I need a favor. Randall was working late last night on the scare floor.
我非常需要他用的门卡
I really need the key for the door he was using.
你真是好贴心呀
Well, isn't that nice?
猜猜怎么着? 你昨晚没交书面报告
But guess what? You didn't turn in your paperwork last night.
他没... 我... 没交书面报告?
He didn't... I... No paperwork?
本窗口暂停服务
This office is now closed.
不管你有没准备好 我来了
Ready or not, here I come.
我离你越来越近喽
I'm getting warmer.
就快了
Any second now.
- 狼 来 了...  - 你在干嘛?
- Fee, fi, fo...  - What are you doing?
我在找那个孩子
I'm looking for the kid.
- 你把它弄丢了?  - 没有 没有 她刚才...
- You lost it?  - No, no. She was just...
她在这呢
Here she is.
嘿 怎么了?
Hey. What's the matter?
- 我已经告诉你们...  - 好吧 继续
- I already told your buddies...  - All right. Carry on.
兰德尔 谢天谢地 我们要拿小孩怎么办?
Randall. Thank goodness. What are we gonna do about the child?
头条啊 已经上头条了 那个孩子 你在找的那个
The front page. It's on the front page. The child. The one you were after.
你能不能安静点? 难道你觉得我不了解情况吗?
Will you be quiet? Don't you think I'm aware of the situation?
我一整晚都在找它
I was up all night trying to find it.
我对寿司店的面积做了简单的计算分析
I did a simple calculation factoring in the size of the sushi restaurant.
小孩可能逃了!
The child may have escaped!
在我们不确定前先装作什么都没发生 懂吗?
Until we know for sure we're gonna act like nothing happened. Understand?
你只需负责机器 我来搞定那个孩子
You will just get the machine up and running. I'll take care of the kid.
不管是谁把它放出来的 只要被我找到 他们必死无疑
When I find whoever let it out, they're dead.
你怎么还在这里? 走! 赶紧! 走!
Why are you still here? Come on, go! Move! Now!
我走
I'm not here.
他们走了
They're gone.
这不妙 非常糟糕
This is bad, it's so very bad.
他们刚才谈的是什么 机器?
What were they talking about, machine?
谁管呢?
Who cares?
别担心 我们只需要找到她的门 把她送回家
Look, don't panic. All we have to do is call her door and send her home.
没错 没错 我们就只是两个去上班的人
You are right. You are right. We're just two regular Joes on our way to work.
我们会混进去的
We will blend right in.
- 大家早上好啊  - 什么在抖动 咸猪肉吗?
- Top of the morning, fellows.  - What's shakin', bacon?
你减肥了没? 还是少了只腿?
Did you lose weight? Or a limb?
- 你有她的门卡 是吧?  - 当然有
- You have her card key, right?  - Of course.I have her card key
我说了我会拿到门卡 我去了而且拿到了
I told you I'd get her card key. I went and got her card key.
现在我有她的门卡
Now I have her card key.
好 开始吧
OK. Here we go.
自己保重 不要随便跑进衣柜了
Take care of yourself. Try not to run through any more closets.
迈克 这不是她的门
Mike, that's not her door.
你在说什么? 这当然是她的门 当然是
What are you talking about? Of course it's her door. It's her door.
不 她的门是白色的 上面有花
No. Her door was white and it had flowers on it.
不 肯定是昨晚太黑你没看清 这就是她的门
No. It must have been dark last night because this is its door.
嘿 你听到没有? 那里感觉很有趣
Hey, you hear that? Sounds like fun in there.
好啦 给我寄张明信片 孩子 收信人是迈克·华斯基 别忘了
OK. Send me a postcard, kid. That's Mike Wazowski, care of
22号 帮你恢复正常生活的迈克·华斯基
22 Mike Wazowski, you-got-your-life-back Lane.
很好 祝你旅途愉快
Very good. Now bon voyage.
再见 来吧 看这棍子 看到棍子没? 去捡吧
Bye-bye. Come on. Look at the stick. See the stick? Go get the stick.
- 去捡啊  - 迈克 这不是阿布的门
- Go fetch.  - Mike, this isn't Boo's door.
- 阿布? 阿布是什么?  - 我决定这么叫她
- Boo? What's Boo?  - That's what I decided to call her.
有问题吗?
There a problem?
小苏 你不应该给它取名字
Sulley, you're not supposed to name it.
一旦你给它取名 你就会对它产生感情
Once you name it, you start getting attached to it.
它从哪里来 现在就把它放回哪里去 不然我发誓...
Now put that thing back where it came from, or so help me...
嘿 我们在排练公司即将上映的剧本 剧名叫做...
Hey. We're rehearsing a scene for the upcoming company play called...
把那东西放回原位 否则有你好看
Put That Thing Back Where It Came From or So Help Me.
这是一个音乐剧
It's a musical.
# 把那东西放回原位否则我发誓 #
# Put that thing back where it came from or so help me #
# 我发誓 我发誓 #
# So help me, so help me #
好 停
And cut.
我们还在努力 这个剧正在排 但我们需要引座员
We're still working on it. It's in progress, but we need ushers.
小苏 我受够了 说再见吧... 它跑哪里去了? 你做了什么?
Sulley, I've had enough. Say goodbye to... Where did it go? What did you do?
- 她在哪?  - 真见鬼 你又让她跑了?
- Where is she?  - I don't believe it. She got away from you again?
额 那真是... 等等 真是雨过天晴
Well, that is just... Wait a minute. The sun is coming up.
太完美了
This is perfect.
她不见了!
She's gone!
你去哪里? 小苏 拜托了 别费力不讨好了
Where are you going? Sulley, please, don't blow this.
我们差点就破纪录了
We're so close to breaking the record.
其他人会找到孩子 那就是他们的问题了 跟我们没关系
Somebody else will find the kid. It'll be their problem.Not ours.
她不会再烦我们了!
She's out of our hair!
- 你们俩在做什么?  - 他们在排练一部剧
- What are you two doing?  - They're rehearsing a play.
# 她不会再烦我们了 #
# She's out of our hair #
迈克·华斯基! 那么你对那小孩跑出来的事怎么看的 苏利文?
Mike Wazowski! So, what do you think of that kid getting out, Sullivan?
- 很疯狂吧?  - 哦 是的 很疯狂
- Pretty crazy?  - Oh, yeah, crazy.
街上的消息是这小孩是从工厂跑出去的
Word on the street is the kid's been traced back to this factory.
- 你没见到什么吧?  - 额...
- You haven't seen anything?  - Well...
没有 不可能
No. No way.
但是如果这是自己人干的 我打赌是维克斯福德
But if it was an inside job, I'd put my money on Waxford.
- 维克斯福德?  - 在第六工作站的
- Waxford?  - The one at station six.
- 他贼眉鼠眼的  - 嘿 维克斯福德
- He's got them shifty eyes.  - Hey, Waxford.
- 小苏啊!  - 迈克·华斯基!
- Sulley!  - Michael Wazowski!
昨晚是有史以来最糟糕的晚上了 糟糕透顶!
Last night was one of the worst nights of my entire life, bar none!
- 我以为你在乎我  - 亲爱的 拜托
- I thought you cared about me.  - Honey, please.
- 我以为你喜欢寿司  - 寿司! 寿司!
- I thought you liked sushi.  - Sushi! Sushi!
你认为这只是因为寿司?
You think this is about sushi?
华斯基
Wazowski.
迈克!
Michael!
该死
Men.
呼吸 继续呼吸
Breathe. Keep breathing.
- 小孩在哪?  - 小孩?
- Where's the kid?  - Kid?
- 什么小孩?  - 它在工厂里 不是吗?
- What kid?  - It's here in the factory, isn't it?
这可不怪我
You are not putting this on me.
要是昨晚你没作弊 它根本不会跑出来
It never would have gotten out if you hadn't been cheating last night.
作弊? 作弊 对
Cheating? Cheating. Right.
好 我知道这事怎么解决了
OK. I think I know how to make this all go away.
五分钟后哨声响起会发生什么?
What happens when the whistle blows in five minutes?
- 我可以休息?  - 大家都去吃午餐
- I get a timeout?  - Everyone goes to lunch.
也就意味着吓人车间会...
Which means the scare floor will be...
- 被粉刷?  - 空无一人
- Painted?  - Empty.
会空无一人 你这个蠢货
It'll be empty, you idiot.
看到钟了没?
You see that clock?
分针秒针都指向12的时候
When the big hand is pointing up and the little hand is pointing up,
我会把那小孩的门弄到我的工作站
the kid's door will be in my station.
一旦过了十二点半
But when the big hand points down,
门就会消失
the door will be gone.
你必须在那之前把小孩送回去
You have until then to put the kid back.
明白了吗?
Get the picture?
阿布!
Boo!
- 不  - 嘿 说你呢 站住
- No.  - Hey, you. Halt.
就是他
He's the one.
- 广告里的是他  - 就是他
- The one from the commercial.  - That's him.
- 能给我们签个名吗?  - 噢 好的 没问题
- Can we get an autograph?  - Oh, sure. No problem.
送给我女儿 斯蒂芬妮
Make that out to Stephanie, my daughter.
好的 我看看
Yes. Let's see.
"致以最好的问候 你的恐怖朋友..."
"From your scary friend. Best wishes..."
所以我就说 "要是你再敢这么和我说话 咱俩就完蛋"
So, then I said, "If you talk to me like that again, we're through".
- 她说什么了?  - 你知道我老妈
- What'd she say?  - You know my mom.
- 她把我关进房间  - 回头见 伙计 放轻松
- She sent me to my room.  - See you guys later. Take it easy.
倒光光
Bottoms up.
阿布!
Boo!
嗨
Hi.
你好啊 你叫什么?
Well, hello, there. What's your name?
迈克·华斯基
Mike Wazowski.
小苏!
Sulley!
噢 小苏
Oh, Sulley.
好的 小苏 别躲了
OK, Sulley, come on.
嘿! 你们看到小苏了吗?
Hey! You guys seen Sulley anywhere?
- 抱歉 没有  - 小苏!
- Nope, sorry.  - Sulley!
伙计 华斯基好像又有麻烦了
Boy, Wazowski looks like he's in trouble.
2319! 2319警报!
2319! We have a 2319!
完了
Oh, dear.
小苏!
Sulley!
小苏 老兄 我有个好消息
Sulley. Great news, pal.
有办法了 不过我们得抓紧时间
I got us a way out of this mess, but we gotta hurry.
它人呢?
Where is it?
小苏 这是个垃圾块
Sull, that's a cube of garbage.
她稚嫩的声音还在我耳边回响
I can still hear her little voice.
- 迈克·华斯基  - 我也能听见
- Mike Wazowski.  - I can hear it too.
- 迈克·华斯基!  - 这里面究竟藏了几个小孩?
- Mike Wazowski!  - How many kids you got in there?
迈克·华斯基!
Mike Wazowski!
- 猫咪!  - 阿布!
- Kitty!  - Boo!
阿布 你没事 我担心死你了 我...
Boo, you're all right. I was so worried. I was...
别再从我身边跑开 小姑娘
Don't you ever run away from me again, young lady.
看到你没事真好
But I'm so glad you're safe.
多么有爱的老爸啊
My, what an affectionate father.
事实上 她是我堂姐的...
Actually, she's my cousin's sister's...
- 好了 小苏 别聊了 该走了  - 迈克·华斯基
- Ok，Sulley. That's enough. Let's go.  - Mike Wazowski.
是的 孩子 让开 我们...
Yeah. Step aside, kid. We're in a...
- 能不能别惹阿布笑?  - 拜托 我才没
- Will you stop making Boo laugh?  - I didn't. Come on.
我还是没弄明白 你找到阿布的门了?
I still don't understand. You got Boo's door?
待会再解释 快过来
I'll explain later. Run.
快 快跑 快 保佑一定在 一定要在
OK. Let's move, let's move let's move. Come on. Please be there. Please be there please be there.
- 它在 兰德尔没说谎  - 兰德尔?
- There it is, just like Randall said.  - Randall?
等等 阿布 嘿
Wait a minute. Boo, hey.
1 2 3 4 把小孩送回去 一切恢复正常
One, two, three, four, get the kid through the door. We are gonna get our lives back.
- 噩梦就要结束了 怎么了?  - 没关系 阿布
- The nightmare is over. What's the matter?  - It's OK, Boo.
- 是时候了  - 迈克 你怎么想的?
- It's time to move.  - Mike, what are you thinking?
- 我们不能相信兰德尔 他想抓阿布  - 管它的? 赶紧啊
- We can't trust Randall. Randall's after Boo. - Who cares? Let's go.
- 只有一次机会  - 不 这不对劲
- This is a limited-time offer.  - No. I don't like this.
小苏 你想找回她的门 这就是
Look, Sulley, you wanted her door and there it is.
- 赶快行动  - 不 迈克
- Now let's move.  - No, Mike.
你非要我证明一切都正常吗? 好吧
You want me to prove everything's on the up and up? Fine.
- 他想要门 我找到了  - 等等
- He wants a door, I get a door.  - Wait.
疑神疑鬼的大毛球
Paranoid delusional furball.
迈克!
Mike!
嘿 小苏 一整天都跑哪去了?
Hey, Sulley, where you been all day?
小苏? 小苏!
Sulley? Sulley!
迈克? 迈克?
Mike? Mike?
你在哪?
Where are you?
你在里面吗?
Are you in there?
老兄 你在哪?
Where are you, buddy?
迈克?
Mike?
你在哪?
Where are you?
阿布 干得好
Boo, way to go.
别害怕
It's OK.
兰德尔 你有没有...
Randall, did you have to...
- 没错! 我抓到了那小孩  - 噢 太好了!
- Yes! I got the kid.  - Oh, huzzah!
- 好消息  不过跟我想的不一样  - 快过来帮我
- Great news. Not that I was concerned.  - Get over here and help me.
快 趁我们精力旺盛 小霉怪
Come on, while we're young here, Fungus.
这小孩得减减肥
The kid needs to take off a few pounds.
华斯基! 它在哪 你这个独眼龙白呲?
Wazowski! Where is it, you little one-eyed cretin?
是念白痴 如果你要威胁我 那至少也得发音标准
It's cretin. If you're gonna threaten me, do it properly.
其次 你们这群疯子
Second, you're nuts if you think kidnapping me
别以为绑架我就能打破记录!
is gonna help you cheat your way to the top!
你还以为这一切都是为了那个愚蠢的纪录?
You still think this is about that stupid scare record?
好吧 我确实这么想
Well, I did.
直到你冷笑 我觉得有点不对
Right up until you chuckled like that.
我想我该走了
Now I think I should get out of here.
我要历史性地改革吓人工厂
I'm about to revolutionize the scaring industry.
等我成功了 就连伟大的詹姆斯·P·苏利文
When I do, even the great James P. Sullivan
也得给我干活
is gonna be working for me.
好吧 有些人天生就是劳碌命
Well, somebody's certainly been a busy bee.
首先你得告诉我那小孩在哪
First I need to know where the kid is and you're gonna tell me.
- 我什么都不知道  - 好吧
- I don't know anything.  - Sure.
我不知道 我真不知道
I don't. I don't.
那是什么? 等等 等等 稍等
What's that? Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
拜托 不 别这样 拜托 嘿 嘿
Come on. No, no. Come on. Hey, hey.
嘿 嘿 这玩意在动
Hey, hey. This thing is moving.
我不喜欢这种会动的大家伙 尤其是朝着我
I don't like big moving things that are moving towards me.
不 别这样 嘿!
No. Come on. Hey!
- 兰德尔!  - 和尖叫榨汁机打声招呼
- Randall!  - Say hello to the scream extractor.
你好
Hello.
你去哪? 我们可以谈谈 喝杯咖啡怎么样
Come on. Where you going? We'll talk. Come on. We'll have a latte.
拜托 还有商量的余地的嘛
Come on. We can talk about this.
这是什么?
What is that thing?
等等 等等 不 别这样 不
Wait, wait, wait. No, no, no.
不 快停下来
No. Come on.
救命 来人啊! 救救我!
Help. Help! Help, help!
怎么... 这次你又哪出了岔子?
Oh, for... What did you do wrong this time?
- 我不知道 我校正过了...  - 去检查下机器
- I don't know. I calibrated the...  - Go check the machine.
一定是尖叫阀门出了点问题
There must be something wrong with the scream intake valve.
小霉怪? 小霉怪? 喜欢车吗?
Fungus? Fungus? You like cars?
我有辆超酷的车 要是你放我走 我就
Cuz I got a really nice car. If you let me go, I'll give you a ride
载你一程 求你了 小霉怪
in the car. Please, Fungus.
很抱歉 华斯基 兰德尔不许我和
I'm sorry, Wazowski, but Randall said I'm not allowed
他邪恶计划的受害者来往
to fraternize with victims of his evil plot.
发生什么事了? 华斯基呢?
What happened? Where's Wazowski?
他在哪?
Where is he?
- 快  - 太疯狂了 他要杀了我们
- Come on.  - This is crazy. He's gonna kill us.
可能被污染
That could be contaminated.
我们快离开这里!
We gotta get out of here now!
去一个遥远的地方 开始新的生活 再见 怪兽公司
We could start a whole new life somewhere far away. Goodbye, Monsters, Inc.
再见了 沃特努斯先生
Goodbye, Mr. Waternoose.
- 不 迈克 等等  - 嘿 你要干嘛?
- No, Mike, wait.  - Hey, what are you doing?
- 跟我来 我有个主意  - 不 不 不 不要 不
- Follow me. I have an idea.  - No, no, no, no, no.
- 演习结束  - 不 不行 不行不行
- Simulation terminated.  - No, no, no, no, no.
你在做什么? 是要你去吓唬他 不是哄他睡觉
What was that? You're trying to scare the kid, not lull it to sleep.
我想弄成蛇一样的忍者
I was going for a snake/ninja approach
还发出嘶嘶声
with a little hissing.
我告诉过你多少次了? 你得有架势
How many times do I have to tell you? It's all about presence.
- 进去时得穷凶极恶的  - 沃特努斯先生!
- About how you enter the room.  - Mr. Waternoose!
詹姆斯 你来得正好
James, perfect timing.
不 不 先生 你不明白
No, no, sir. You don't understand.
- 给这群菜鸟上堂课  - 不行
- Show these monsters how it's done.  - I can't.
- 先生 你先听我说  - 所有人 注意了
- Sir, you have to listen to me.  - Pay attention. Everyone
他是最棒的
You're about to see the best in the business.
- 重启演习车间  - 可是先生!
- Reset the simulator.  - But sir!
- 晚安 宝贝儿!  - 晚安 妈妈
- Good night, sweetheart.  - Night, Mom.
- 猫咪!  - 不 阿布 不!
- Kitty!  - No, Boo, no!
- 怒吼一声  - 没时间讨论这个!
- Give us a big loud roar.  - There's no time for this!
- 你还在等什么? 快吼啊  - 可是先生...
- Come on. What are you waiting for? Roar.  - But, sir...
吼!
Roar!
干得好 干得漂亮 詹姆斯
Well done. Well done, James.
- 阿布?  - 好了 先生们
- Boo?  - All right, gentlemen.
- 这边请  - 我希望你们今天有所收获
- Right this way.  - I hope you've learned a lesson today.
阿布
Boo.
阿布 是我
Boo, it's me.
- 是那个孩子!  -  先生 她无害的
- The child!  - Sir, she isn't toxic.
- 这也许听上去很疯狂 但相信我  - 阿布?
- I konw it sounds crazy, but trust me.  - Boo?
不 不 别害怕 没事
No, no, no, no, it's OK.
我只是... 别害怕
I was just... No.
不 别害怕 那不是真的
No, don't be scared. That wasn't real.
那只是... 我刚刚只是...
It's just a... I was just...
- 阿布  - 想用那小女孩做实验
- Boo.  - Test it out on that sweet little girl.
- 阿布  - 拥有她 他还想杀了我们灭口
- Boo.  - Have her, he is trying to kill us.
- 都是兰德尔的错  - 兰德尔?
- This whole thing is Randall's fault.  - Randall?
我们现在就可以带你去他藏在工厂里的秘密工作室
Yes. And we can take you to his secret lab which is right here in this factory.
怎么会有这种事?  怎么会搞成这样?
How could this happen? How could this happen?
还有人知道吗?
Does anyone else know about this?
- 没有 先生  - 很好
- No, sir.  - Good.
公司的负面消息已经够多了
This company can't afford any more bad publicity.
现在 我们最好还是
Now, before we do anything else,
先处理下这孩子
let's take care of the child.
我从没想过事情会变成这样
I never thought things would come to this.
至少不会在我的公司
Not in my factory.
很抱歉把你们卷进来
I'm sorry you boys got mixed up in this.
特别是你 詹姆斯
Especially you, James.
现在可以将一切重新恢复正常
But now we can set everything straight again.
为了公司的利益
For the good of the company.
先生? 这不是她的门
Sir? That's not her door.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
这是为你们准备的
It's yours.
不!
No!
阿布!
Boo!
不! 不! 不要啊!
No! No! No, no, no, no!
太晚了 天才 我们被驱逐出境了!
It's too late. We're banished, genius!
这是人类的世界
We're in the human world.
多么棒的想法啊 回去找你的老伙计沃特努斯
What a great idea, going to your old pal Waternoose.
可惜他也有份
Too bad he was in on the whole thing.
要是你听我的就没事了
All you had to do was listen to me.
一次就好! 但你不肯 你根本不听?
Just once! But you didn't, did you?
你到现在还不听!
You're still not listening!
吃我一拳!
Take that!
欢迎来到喜马拉雅山
Welcome to the Himalayas.
"可怕的" 真难以置信
"Abominable". Can you believe that?
我看起来很可怕吗?
Do I look abominable to you?
为什么不叫我可爱的雪怪
Why can't they call me the Adorable Snowman
或善解人意的雪怪?
or the Agreeable Snowman, for crying out loud?
我可是个大好人 来点雪糕?
I'm a nice guy. Snow cone?
别 别担心 这是柠檬味的
No, don't worry. It's lemon.
你呢 大个子? 要雪糕吗?
How about you, big fella? Snow cone?
你看到她看我的眼神了吗?
Did you see the way she looked at me?
可怜的人 我理解 被驱逐出境是很难接受
Poor guy. I understand. It ain't easy being banished.
就拿我的好兄弟 大脚来说
Take my buddy, Bigfoot.
他被驱逐出境的时候 用毒藤弄了个大尿布
When he was banished, he fashioned an enormous diaper out of poison ivy.
弄的像顶皇冠 戴在头上
Wore it on his head like a tiara.
自称是痒痒帝 你们比他强多了
Called himself King Itchy. It won't be so hard for you guys thougn.
看看你们多幸运?
How lucky can you get?
- 和好朋友一起被驱逐出境  - 他不是我的朋友
- Banished with your best friend.  - He is not my friend.
我以为你们是好兄弟 看你俩在雪地里搂搂抱抱的...
I just assumed you were buddies, you know. When I saw you in the snow hugging...
瞧瞧那个混蛋 他毁了我一生 为了什么?
Look at that big jerk. Ruined my life. And for what?
一个小破孩!
A stupid kid!
就是因为你 我才被困在这冰天雪地的荒原
Because of you I am now stuck in this frozen wasteland.
荒原? 你想说乐园吧
Wasteland? I think you mean wonderland.
瞧瞧这惊艳的大雪?
How about all this fabulous snow?
还有世界上最可爱的东西
And wait till you see the local village.
这里的小村庄 更不必说免费的牦牛奶
Cutest thing in the world. I haven't mentioned the free yaks' milk.
- 你刚刚说什么?  - 牦牛奶
- What did you say?  - Yaks' milk.
给牦牛挤奶可不简单
Milking a yak ain't exactly a picnic.
不过挑干净牛奶里面的牛毛再喝 可是很有营养哟
Once you pick the hairs out it's nutritious.
不 关于村子 那里有小孩吗?
No, something about a village. Are there kids in it?
小孩? 当然 淘气包 爱哭鬼 爬在石头上的小孩
Kids? Sure. Tough kids, sissy kids, kids who climb on rocks.
- 在哪儿?  - 山脚下
- Where is it?  - At the bottom of the mountain.
- 得走3天  - 3天?
- Around three-day hike.  - Three days?
我们现在就得去那
We need to get there now.
你想去村子?
You wanna go to the village?
第一条 永远... 不
Rule number one out here, always... No.
千万别再暴风雪天出门
Never go out in a blizzard.
我们得去救阿布
We need to get to Boo.
阿布? 那我们呢?
Boo? What about us?
自从她出现以后 我说什么你都不听
Ever since the kid came in, you've ignored everything I've said,
瞧瞧我们的下场! 我们本来都快破记录了 小苏
and now look where we are! We were about to break the record, Sulley.
- 要不是这 我们早就破纪录了  - 这都不重要了
- We would have had it made.  - None of that matters now.
都不重要? 等等
None of it matters? Wait a second.
这一切都不重要?
None of it matters?
好吧 行 你真行
OK. No, good. Great.
终于真相大白了 是吗?
So now the truth comes out, doesn't it?
瞧瞧这个? 雪糕没有了
Would you look at that? We're out of snow cones.
我去外面再做些
Let me just go outside and make some more.
小苏 那我们努力得来的一切呢?
Sulley, what about everything we ever worked for?
也不重要吗?
Does that matter?
希莉娅呢?
What about Celia?
我永远... 再也没机会见到她了
I am never... never gonna see her again.
这不重要吗?
Doesn't that matter?
那么我呢?
And what about me?
我是你的好搭档 是你最好的朋友
I'm your pal. I'm your best friend.
我也不重要了吗?
Don't I matter?
对不起 迈克
I'm sorry, Mike.
害你被困在这儿
I'm sorry we're stuck out here.
我不是故意的
I didn't mean for this to happen.
但是阿布现在有危险
But Boo's in trouble.
我有办法救她 只要我们...
I think there might be a way to save her if we can just get...
我们? 等等 你说我们?
We? Whoa. We?
不 没有"我们"了 我不会在帮你了 老兄
No. There's no "we" this time, pal.
要是你想离开这 在外面冻死
If you want to go out there and freeze to death,
我一点意见都没有
you be my guest.
因为这都是你自找的
Because you're on your own.
嘿 我又做了些新的雪糕!
Hey, I got more snow cones!
来嘛 乔治 我知道你行的
Come on, George. I know you can do this.
我给你选了个容易的门
I picked out an easy door for you.
在尼泊尔 很美 非常安静
In Nepal. Nice, quiet Nepal.
你说得对 好啦 拿去
You know, you're right. Here. Take this.
大干一场 乔治
Go get 'em, Georgie.
小心点 我来了
Look out. Coming through.
- 抱歉 乔治  - 嗨 你不能这么...
- Sorry, George.  - Hey, you can't just...
警报23...
Twenty-three...
都给我让开!
Out of the way!
一开始我就不该相信你
Finally. I never should have trusted you with this.
因为你 我将我最顶尖的怪兽驱逐出境了
Because of you, I had to banish my top scarer.
有了这个机器 我们根本不需要怪兽
With this machine, we won't need scarers.
那是苏利文他活该
Sullivan got what he deserved.
苏利文比你厉害多了
Sullivan was twice the scarer you will ever be.
猫咪!
Kitty!
- 猫咪!  - 苏利文?
- Kitty!  - Sullivan?
- - 猫咪!  - 对不起 阿布
- Kitty!  - Sorry, Boo.
拦住他!
Stop him!
我送你回家
Let's get you home.
把他干掉!
Finish him off!
苏利文 我等这一刻已经很久了
You don't know how long I've wanted to do that, Sullivan.
迈克?
Mike?
- 我不是不关心那小孩  - 迈克 你还不明白
- It's not that I don't care.  - Mike, you don't understand.
不 我知道 我就是很生气 就是这样
Yes, I do. I was just mad, that's all.
我得冷静下 不过你不该丢下我
I needed some time to think, but you shouldn't have left me out there.
- 有人打我  - 我没揍你
- I'm being attacked.  - I'm not attacking you.
我只是实话实说 听我说完 我们是搭档
I'm trying to be honest. Hear me out. You and I are a team.
没有什么比我们的友谊还重要
Nothing is more important than our friendship.
我知道 他太敏感了
I know. He's too sensitive.
拜托 伙计 你哭了 我也会哭的
Come on, pal. If you start crying, I'm gonna cry.
这样会没完没了
And I'll never get through this.
很抱歉当时没和你一起 不过我回来了
I'm sorry I wasn't there for you, but I am now.
小苏 我在对你敞开心扉呢 你就不能专心点
Sulley, I am baring my soul here. The least you can do is pay attention.
看 是兰德尔
Look at that. It's Randall.
快跑
Come on.
给我起来 别让其余人看见了
Get up. There can't be any witnesses.
不会的
There won't be.
你回来了我很高兴 迈克
I'm glad you came back, Mike.
总得有个人照顾你 大毛球
Somebody's gotta take care of you, you big hairball.
- 小甜甜 我现在没时间解释  - 快跟上
- Schmoopsie-pooh, I really can't talk.  - Come on.
迈克 如果你现在不立马告诉我这是怎么回事
Michael, if you don't tell me what's going on right now,
我们之间就拜拜! 听见了吗? 拜拜!
we are through! You hear me? Through!
我告诉你怎么回事
Here's the truth.
你知道他们要找的那个小孩吧? 小苏把她带回来了
You know the kid that they're looking for? Sulley let her in.
我们想把她送回去 但沃特努斯另有阴谋
We tried to send her back, but Waternoose had this secret plot,
现在兰德尔就在我们身后 想杀了我们!
and now Randall's right behind us and trying to kill us!
你觉得我会相信吗 迈克·华斯基?
You expect me to believe that pack of lies, Mike Wazowski?
迈克·华斯基啊
Mike Wazowski.
我爱你 小甜甜!
I love you, schmoopsie-pooh!
- 嘿!  - 笨蛋
- Hey!  - Idiots.
当心 让让
Look out. Coming through.
让一下 让让 快点 快点
Make way. Move it. Hurry up, hurry up.
- 他们在那儿  - 员工们 请注意
- There they are.  - Attention, employees.
兰德尔 鲍格斯刚刚打破了尖叫纪录
Randall Boggs has just broken the all-time scare record.
不 我没打破 都给我让开
No, I didn't. Get out of my way.
拿下他 大眼儿熊
Go get 'em, googly bear.
它在那儿
There it is.
别围着我 让开
Get off my tail. Let go.
- 你在干嘛?  - 抓住我 迈克
- What are you doing?  - Grab on, Mike.
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
- 小苏 你要干嘛?  - 找到阿布的那扇门 然后找个工作站
- Sulley, what are we doing?  - Get Boo's door and find a station.
真是好主意 简单 又疯狂
What a plan. Simple, yet insane.
- 哇  - 天啊
- Whoa.  - Oh, boy.
抓紧了!
Hold on!
别往下看!
Don't look down!
我要吐了
I'm gonna be sick.
哦 不
Oh, no.
不!
No!
- 阿布的那扇门  - 它在那儿
- Boo's door.  - There it is.
我们怎么才能过去?
How are we supposed to get to it now?
这是个死胡同 小苏
It's a dead end, Sulley.
- 他来了  - 逗她笑
- There he is.  - Make her laugh.
- 小苏!  - 快点!
- Sulley!  - Just do it!
- 把门打开  - 他来了
- Get it open.  - Here he comes.
把孩子交出来
Give me that kid.
- 怎么不把我们流放到这样的地方?  - 我们得找到另一扇门
- Why couldn't we get banished here?  - We gotta find another door.
快看! 阿布的门
Look! Boo's door.
- 他追过来了 快点!  - 把手给我
- There he is. Hurry up!  - Give me your hand.
- 快点 这是推拉门  - 哦 对
- Come on, it slides.  - Right. Right.
你先跳 我跟着你
Jump. I'm right behind you.
跟上
Come on.
快点 赶紧的!
Hurry up. Keep moving!
进去
Get inside.
奇怪了
That was weird.
迈克啊?
Mike?
- 抱歉 兄弟  - 没事
- Sorry, buddy.  - OK.
打疼你了吧 小蜥蜴
I hope that hurt, lizard boy.
干得好 兄弟 我们甩掉他了
Great job, buddy. We lost him.
阿布!
Boo!
不!
No!
和你合作真是太愉快了
Nice working with you.
- 把门打开!  - 我正开着呢!
- Get it open!  - I'm trying!
- 把门打开!  - 快点 进来
- Open the door!  - Come on, get in here.
阿布!
Boo!
他们在那儿!
There they are!
小苏 你要干嘛? 小苏!
Sulley, what are you doing? Sulley!
- 看来我们赶上列车了  - 看到他们了吗?
- Looks like we caught the express.  - Do you see them?
就在前面
Straight ahead.
- 猫咪  - 阿布
- Kitty.  - Boo.
看看这个最受欢迎的怪兽啊
Look at everybody's favorite scarer now.
你这个蠢货 可怜虫 垃圾
You stupid, pathetic waste.
你坐头把交椅的时间够长了 苏利文 风水轮流转啊
You've been number one for too long, Sullivan. Now your time is up.
别担心 我会好好关照这孩子的
And don't worry. I'll take good care of the kid.
不!
No!
她一点也不怕你了
She's not scared of you anymore.
看来你得换份工作了
Looks like you're out of a job.
好了 把他飞过来 展示下你的经典大招
OK, over the plate. Let's see the old stuff.
使劲丢 宝贝儿
Chuck him, baby.
一个投球 他就出局了
Here's the pitch and he is out of here.
- 妈妈 房子里又进了一只鳄鱼  - 又有鳄鱼?
- Mama, another gator got in the house.  - Another gator?
把铁锹给我!
Give me that shovel. There!
干掉它 妈妈 干掉鳄鱼
Get him, Mama. Get that gator.
- 愿意帮个忙吗 小迈?  - 乐意之极
- Care to do the honors, Mikey? - With pleasure.
这就对了 阿布 你做到了
That's right, Boo. You did it.
你打败他了
You beat him.
走吧
Come on.
好了 阿布 该回家了
OK, Boo, it's time to go home.
好好照顾自己 要乖 知道吗?
Take care of yourself and be a good girl, OK?
- 哦 不  - 停电了 逗她笑
- Oh, no.  - The power's out. Make her laugh.
接下来我要施展我的成名绝技
All right. I got a move here that'll bring down the house.
- 抱歉 她没看到  - 什么?
- Sorry. She didn't see that.  - What?
什么 你忘了把她的帽子拿下来了 大个子?
What, did you forget to check if her hood was up, you big dope?
迈克叔叔 别在小朋友面前大吼大叫
Uncle Mike, try not to yell in front of her.
- 我们是需要逗她笑的  - 哦对
- You know we need her to laugh.  - Right.
嘿 阿布 开个玩笑 看
Hey, Boo. Just kidding. Look.
很搞笑 是吧? 看...
Funny, right? See, with the...
我很卖力的 孩子 怎么了?
These are the jokes, kid. What's happening?
抓住了
Hold on.
等那扇门到了工作站 就切断电源
When the door lands in the station, cut the power.
你们就能抓到那孩子和这一切的罪魁祸首
You'll have the child and the criminals responsible for this whole mess.
好极了 欢迎大会 我们该怎么办?
Great. A welcoming committee. What are we gonna do?
我们是儿童检测署 交出孩子 慢慢走出来
This is the CDA. Come out slowly with the child in plain sight.
好吧 好吧 被你们抓住了
OK, OK, you got us.
我们在这 孩子也在这
Here we are. Here's the kid.
我会合作的 但在把我带走之前 我要说件事
I'll cooperate, but before you take us away, I have one thing to say.
- 去抓吧  - 2319号警报
- Catch.  - 2319.
我们被有毒物体击中
We have a toxic projectile.
- 抓住嫌疑人  - 拦住他!
- After the suspect.  - Stop him!
- 快走  - 别让他跑了
- Come on.  - Don't let them get away.
等一下 回来 孩子在他那里
Wait. Come back. He has the child.
苏利文 苏利文!
Sullivan. Sullivan!
把孩子给我 把她给我!
Give me the child. Give her to me!
把门打开 把门打开!
Open this door. Open this door!
快停下
Stop it.
别这样
Don't do it.
- 快点  - 别进去
- Come on.  - Don't go in that room.
我想我甩掉他了 阿布 你安全了
I think we stopped him, Boo. You're safe now.
你要乖乖的 好吗?
You be a good girl, OK?
- 你太过分了 詹姆斯  - 这是她家 别再打扰她了
- This has gone far enough, James.  - She's home. Leave her alone.
我不能 她知道的太多了
I can't do that. She's seen too much.
- 你也是  - 并不是非得这样
- You both have.  - It doesn't have to be this way.
我别无选择 时代不同了
I have no choice. Times have changed.
- 恐吓已经满足不了能源的需要了  - 那你就绑架孩子?
- Scaring isn't enough anymore.  - But kidnapping?
为了不让公司倒闭 就算绑架1000个孩子我也愿意
I'll kidnap 1,000 children before I let the company die.
挡路的人都得死!
And I'll silence anyone who gets in my way!
不!
No!
- 晚安 妈妈  - 晚安 宝贝儿
- Night, Mom.  - Night, sweetheart.
- 晚安 妈妈  - 这是什么?
- Night, Mom.  - What is this?
演习结束 演习结束
Simulation terminated. Simulation terminated.
好吧 不管你们发没发现
Well, I don't know about the rest of you guys,
反正我是发现了好几处大错误
but I spotted several big mistakes.
但怎么...
But how did...
猜怎么着? 我们再看一遍我最喜欢的那段 怎么样?
You know what? Let's watch my favorite part again. Shall we?
为了不让公司倒闭 就算绑架1000个孩子我也愿意
I'll kidnap 1,000 children before I let this company die.
- 跟我们走  - 你们在干什么?
- Come with us.  - What are you doing?
把手拿开 你们不能抓我
Take your hands off. You can't arrest me.
这下你高兴了吧 苏利文 你毁了公司
I hope you're happy, Sullivan. You destroyed this company.
怪兽电力公司要关门了! 员工们再去哪收集尖叫?
Monsters, Incorporated is dead! Where will everyone get their scream?
是你让能源危机更严重了!
The energy crisis will only get worse because of you!
站住别动 老大想要见你们
Stay where you are. Number one wants to talk to you.
注意了
Attention.
你们好 小伙子们
Hello, boys.
- 是萝丝?  - 是萝丝?
- Roz?  - Roz?
两年半卧底工作差点功亏一篑
Two and a half years of undercover work were almost wasted
就因为你救了那个孩子 苏利文
when you intercepted that child, Mr. Sullivan.
当然 如果没有你帮忙
Of course, without your help,
我发现不了这一切都是沃特努斯在幕后主使
I never would have known that this went all the way up to Waternoose.
现在 这个女孩
Now, about the girl.
我只想把她送回家
I just want to send her home.
很好
Very good.
- 给我送个粉碎机  - 什么? 你要...
- Bring me a door shredder.  - What? You mean...
你是说我再也见不到她了?
You mean I can't see her again?
只能这样了
That's the way it has to be.
给你五分钟
I'll give you five minutes.
- 再见了 孩子  - 迈克·华斯基
- Well, so long, kid.  - Mike Wazowski.
好吧
Yeah.
哦 阿布
Boo.
和你一起很开心
It's been fun.
走吧 好好长大
Go ahead. Go grow up.
不行 阿布...
But, Boo...
阿布
Boo.
看啊 你知道...
Look at that. You know...
真可爱 是啊
That's cute. Yeah.
阿布...
Boo...
好吧 你真好
Well, that's very nice.
来!
Come here, you!
哦 他是快乐熊
Oh, he's a happy bear
再也不会有怪物从衣橱里出来吓唬你了 对吧?
Nothing's coming out of your closet to scare you anymore, right?
对啊
Yeah.
再见了 阿布
Goodbye, Boo.
猫咪
Kitty.
猫咪得走了
Kitty has to go.
嘣
Boo.
猫咪?
Kitty?
同志们 就当一切都没发生过
None of this ever happened, gentlemen.
我不想看到任何关于这件事情的记录
And I don't want to see any paperwork on this.
开车吧
Take him away.
我猜我们今天可以下班了
I bet we get the rest of the day off.
你个蠢货 工厂要关门了
You idiot. They're gonna shut down the factory.
墙升上去的时候 你真应该看看沃特努斯的那张脸
When that wall went up, you should have seen Waternoose's face.
真想把他照下来
I hope we get a copy of that tape.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
来吧 兄弟 高兴点 我们成功了!
Come on, pal. Cheer up. We did it!
我们把阿布送回家了
We got Boo home.
虽然 我们让公司面临倒闭
Sure, we put the factory in the toilet and
成百上千的人要失业了
hundreds of people will be out of work.
更别提能源短缺了 愤怒的人们会追着我们打
Not to mention the mob that will come after us when there's no power,
但至少我们听到一点笑声了 对吧?
but at least we had some laughs, right?
笑声
Laughs.
开了吗? 喂? 喂? 试试音效
Is this thing on? Hello? Hello? Testing.
晚上好 很高兴见到你
Good evening. Nice to see you.
你房间真不错
It's great to be here in your room.
你从哪里来的?
Where are you from?
你上幼儿园 对吧? 我喜欢幼儿园
You're in kindergarten, right? I love kindergarten.
那是我最快乐的时光
Best three years of my life.
这辈子最快乐的 但我喜欢运动
Of my life. But I love sports.
躲避球是我的最爱 我总是最敏捷的那个
Dodgeball was the best. I was the fastest one out there.
当然了 我就是那个球
Of course, I was the ball.
我就是那个球 好吧...
I was the ball, see...
好吧
All right.
万分感谢 这周我都会来
Thanks a lot. I'll be here all week.
别忘了给点小费
Remember to tip your waitresses.
干得好 小迈 你在第一个孩子那里就完成了今天的任务量
Great job, Mikey. You filled your quota on the first kid of the day.
很棒吧 只有有绝佳喜剧天赋的人
Not bad. Only somebody with perfect comedic timing
才能一次就收集这么多的能源
could produce this much energy in one shot.
但这和笑声的能量是尖叫的能量的十倍
And the fact that laughter is ten times more powerful than scream
一点关系都没有?
had nothing to do with it?
大眼儿熊 你 过来嘛
Googly bear, come here, you.
- 小甜甜!  - 大眼儿熊
- Schmoopsie-pooh!  - Googly.
姐妹们 停一下 停 停
Girls, stop, stop, stop.
迈克 你真迷人
Michael, you're such a charmer.
- 你把杂志带来了吗?  - 刚送来 一大箱呢
- Did you bring the magazine?  - They just delivered a whole box.
让我看看!
Let me see it!
小苏和我上封面了 是吧?
Sulley and I made the cover, right?
真难以置信!
I don't believe it!
大眼儿熊
Googly bear.
我上封面啦!
I'm on the cover of a magazine!
太棒了
This is great.
- 嘿 小苏  - 嘿 迈克
- Hey, Sulley.  - Hey, Mike.
- 我在...  - 我想给你看样东西
- I was...  - There's something I want to show you.
闭上眼睛 跟我走
Close your eyes. Follow me.
快点 不准偷看
Come on. No peeking.
一直走 别停
Keep coming, keep coming.
- 快点  - 迈克!
- Come on.  - Mike!
跟着我磁性的嗓音走
Follow the sultry sound of my voice.
好 停
OK, stop.
睁开眼睛
Open 'em.
迈克 这是...
Mike, is that...
抱歉我用了很长时间才修好 兄弟
Sorry it took so long, pal.
碎成太多块了
There was a lot of wood to go through.
只有一块不少门才好用
It only works if you have every piece.
阿布?
Boo?
猫咪!
Kitty!
# 如果我是个富翁 #
# If I were a rich man #
# 有个一两百万的 #
# With a million or two #
# 我要住在阁楼上 #
# I'd live in a penthouse #
# 周围美景尽收眼底 #
# In a room with a view #
# 如果我是个帅哥 #
# And if I were handsome #
不可能
No way.
说不定呢
It could happen.
# 所有的梦想都已实现 #
# Those dreams do come true #
# 但如果没有你我会一无所有 #
# I wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have you #
# 没有你我会一无所有 #
# Wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have #
# 一无所有 #
# Wouldn't have nothing #
我能来一句吗?
Can I tell you something?
# 这些年我很嫉妒你 #
# For years I have envied #
你嫉妒我
You were green with it.
# 嫉妒你优雅而迷人 #
# Your grace and your charm #
# 要知道 大家都爱你 #
# Everyone loves you, you know #
# 是的 我知道 我知道 #
# Yes, I know, I know, I know #
# 但我不得不承认 #
# But I must admit it #
# 老兄 你总是信守承诺 #
# Big guy, you always come through #
# 没有你我会一无所有 #
# I wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have you #
# 兄弟齐心 #
# You and me together #
# 友谊天长地久 #
# That's how it always should be #
# 没有你的人生毫无意义 #
# One without the other don't mean nothing to me #
# 毫无意义 #
# Nothing to me #
# 是啊 一无所成 #
# Yeah, I wouldn't be nothing #
# 一无所成 #
# No #
# 如果没有你 #
# If I didn't have you to serve #
# 我只是个小眼球 #
# I'm just a punky little eyeball #
# 连着个视神经 #
# And a funky optic nerve #
# 嘿 我从没跟你说过 #
# Hey, I never told you this #
# 有时候我会忧郁 #
# Sometimes I get a little blue #
忧郁很适合你
Looks good on you.
# 我就一无所有 #
# But I wouldn't have nothing #
# 如果没有你 #
# If I didn't have you... #
我们来跳舞
Let's dance.
看 兄弟 我在跳舞!
Look, Ma, I'm dancing!
我能领舞吗?
Would you let me lead?
看啊 这是真的
Look at that. It's true.
大块头跳起舞来这么轻盈
Big guys are light on their feet.
别让我下腰
Don't you dare dip me.
别让我下腰 别让我下腰
Don't you dare dip me, don't you dare dip me.
嗷 我应该先拉伸一下的
Ow. I should have stretched.
# 是啊 我会一无所有 #
# Yes, I wouldn't be nothing #
# 如果没有你 #
# If I didn't have you #
我懂你的 小苏
I know what you mean, Sulley.
# 因为... #
# Because... #
# 我会迷失方向 #
# I wouldn't know where to go #
# 我也是 因为我... #
# Me, too, because I... #
# 也不知如何是好 #
# Wouldn't know what to do #
你怎么老是抢我的部分?
Why do you keep singing my part?
# 一切尽在不言中 #
# I don't have to say it #
啊 还是说出来吧
Ah, say it anyway.
# 因为我们... #
# 'Cause we... #
# 都知道这是实话 #
# Both know it's true #
# 如果没有你我会一无所有 #
# I wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have #
# I wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have you #
# 如果没有你我会一无所有 #
# Wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have you. #
再来一遍
One more time.
唱得好!
It worked!
# 一切尽在不言中 #
# I don't have to say it #
大家怎么都来了?
Where'd everybody come from?
# 因为我们都知道这是实话 #
# 'Cause we both know it's true #
我们回家再唱 大块头
Let's take it home, big guy.
# 如果没有你我会一无所有 #
# I wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have #
# I wouldn't have nothing if I didn't have you #
# 你 你 #
# You, you #
# 不是A E I O... #
# A, E, I, O... #
# 而是你 耶 #
# That means you, yeah. #